{
    "questions" : [
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "25_1_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : There are still about 30 minutes left to start the performance.\nWoman : I see. Then shall we eat something over there?\nMan : good I was a little hungry too, but that's good.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③ ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [1~2] 다음을 듣고 알맞은 그림을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "25_2_img",
            "option_1"      : "① ",
            "option_2"      : "② ",
            "option_3"      : "③ ",
            "option_4"      : "④ ",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : There's a fire, so please change the light bulb.\nMan : Yes. Then can you grab the chair?\nWoman : Yes. I will . Do it carefully",
            "correctAnswer" : "③ ",
            "score"         : "3",
            "isImg"         : "y"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "3. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  네. 급한 일부터 끝냈어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  네. 휴가 다녀와서 제출해요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  네. 휴가 때는 푹 쉬어야지요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  네. 그렇게 특별한 건 없었어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Did you have a good vacation?\nWoman : Yes, I had a good rest. I haven't been on a trip in a long time. Nothing happened to the company in the meantime, right?\nMan : Yes. There was nothing so special",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  네. 그렇게 특별한 건 없었어요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },        
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "4. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  선배를 기다리고 있는 중이야.",
            "option_2"      : "②  이것부터 먼저 끝내고 나가자.",
            "option_3"      : "③  정문 앞에서 만나서 출발할 거야.",
            "option_4"      : "④  나도 그쪽으로 갈 건데 같이 가자.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Where are you going?\nMan : I have a lunch appointment in front of the front door. I'm supposed to meet Minsu.\nWoman : I'm going there too, so let's go together.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  나도 그쪽으로 갈 건데 같이 가자.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "5. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  사전을 잃어버려서 새로 샀어요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  누구한테 빌려 줬는지 모르겠네요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  저는 그것도 모르고 한참 찾았네요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  사전에는 이름을 써 두는 게 좋아요.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : That's really weird. Mina, didn't you see my dictionary on the desk?\nWoman : Oh, the dictionary? You lent it to Minsu yesterday.\nMan : I didn't even know that and I looked for it for a long time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  저는 그것도 모르고 한참 찾았네요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [3~6]다음 대화를 잘 듣고 이어 질 수있는 말을 고르십시오",
            "question"      : "6. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이제 보일러를 켜도 된대요.",
            "option_2"      : "②  너무 오래돼서 그런가 봐요.",
            "option_3"      : "③  수리가 끝나는 대로 빨리 갈게요.",
            "option_4"      : "④  외출을 해야 해서 오후가 좋겠어요.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Well, even if I turn on the boiler, it doesn't get warm. I fixed it last time, and it happens again.\nMan : Oh, do you? Then can we visit now?\nWoman : I want to go out in the afternoon.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  외출을 해야 해서 오후가 좋겠어요.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "7. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  노트북의 무게",
            "option_2"      : "②  노트북의 가격",
            "option_3"      : "③  노트북의 수명",
            "option_4"      : "④  노트북의 성능",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Did you buy a new laptop?\nWoman : Yes. I bought it yesterday and it's really light and good. Would you like to listen.\nMan : Wow, that's so light. I should buy something like this next time. My laptop is heavy, so it's hard to carry around for a long time.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  노트북의 무게",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "8. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "① 아이의 대화 태도",
            "option_2"      : "② 다양한 대화 상황",
            "option_3"      : "③ 가족의 대화 시간",
            "option_4"      : "④ 부모의 대화 방법",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : How do you usually talk to your child? Parents need to talk to their child with interest in their school life or friendship. And you have to let the child express his thoughts and feelings honestly. Children who are used to talking with their parents are full of confidence and have a better social skills.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④ 부모의 대화 방법",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "9. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "① 유리건 물의 증가이유",
            "option_2"      : "② 유리건 물의건 축기간",
            "option_3"      : "③ 유리 건물의 실내 구조",
            "option_4"      : "④ 유리 건물의 이미지 변화",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : You've probably seen a glass building with the whole wall. It is especially common in public buildings such as airports and railway stations. These days, ordinary buildings are often built like this. The reason why glass buildings are increasing is because the appearance is beautiful and various designs are possible, so it is easy to reveal the individuality of the building. It also has the advantage of a shorter construction period than a concrete building.",
            "correctAnswer" : "① 유리건 물의 증가이유",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [7~10] 다음은 무엇에 대한 내용인지 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "10. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "① 사고 피해 상황",
            "option_2"      : "② 사고 방지 대책",
            "option_3"      : "③ 사고 보상 방법",
            "option_4"      : "④ 사고 처리 절차",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : There are many buses that use recycled tires, which are eco-friendly products these days. Accidents with regenerating tires exploding during the bus operation are occurring one after another. In response, the government has ordered to stop using recycled tires until stability is verified. It also said it would strengthen the safety check regulations for all buses. Attention is focused on how much accidents will be reduced with this measure.",
            "correctAnswer" : "② 사고 방지 대책",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "11. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  감정 로봇은 기분에 따라 눈동자가 변한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  감정 로봇은 눈을 맞추면 웃는 표정을 짓는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  감정 로봇은 앞사람의 표정을 따라할 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  감정 로봇은 목소리가 사람 목소리와 비슷하다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Did you see the news about the emotional robot yesterday?\nMan : Yes. Actually, I've seen it in person at the robot exhibition hall. Smile and deliver flowers to people, and move your eyes to match people and eyes. Besides, if the person in front of you makes a sad face, he makes the same face.\nWoman : I was most surprised that the robot's voice changes depending on the mood.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  감정 로봇은 앞사람의 표정을 따라할 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "12. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  대강당 수리 작업이 내일부터 시작된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  공사 기간 동안 3층에 출입하지 못한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  소음을 막기 위한 공사를 실시할 예정이다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  자료실의 자료는 2주 동안 이용할 수 없다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : I would like to inform you. From tomorrow, we are planning to repair the internal wall in the data room on the 3rd floor for 2 weeks. We ask for your understanding as noise due to construction is expected. And during this period, not only the data room but also all areas on the 3rd floor are not allowed. The data in the data room and the computer have been moved to the auditorium on the 5th floor, so if you need it, please use it.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  공사 기간 동안 3층에 출입하지 못한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [11~13] 다음을 듣고 내용과 일치하는 것을 고르십시오. (각 4점)",
            "question"      : "13. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  단거리 선수는 숨을 멈추고 달리는 훈련을 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  장거리 선수는 음식에 특별히 신경을 쓰지 않는다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  단거리 선수는 짧은 시간에 집중적인 훈련을 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  장거리 선수는 힘을 모아 달리는 연습을 주로 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\n Men : Track and field athletes have different parts of special care before the game depending on the event. Long-distance athletes who run a marathon eat enough calories to create energy in their bodies. That's because I can cheer up until the end. On the other hand, players who run short distances, such as a 100-meter run, invest more time in breathing training as the game approaches. Practice getting strong in a short amount of time while running at a certain distance without breathing. ",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  단거리 선수는 숨을 멈추고 달리는 훈련을 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "14. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  장사를 하는 사람의 수를 줄여야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  학교 안에서 장사를 하는 것은 좋지 않다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  장사를 하고 난 후에는 깨끗하게 치워야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  학교에서 축제를 위한 장소를 더 늘려야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : It's the festival period, so the inside of the school is really complicated.\nMan : I know. There are a lot of people doing business here and there.\nWoman: But can I do business in the school every event like this? It looks so messy and it's uncomfortable to pass by....... I feel a little bad because only people who do business use the festival make money.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  학교 안에서 장사를 하는 것은 좋지 않다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "15. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  요즘 연극은 공연 시간이 길어서 부담스럽다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  관객들은 연극의 진행을 방해해서는 안 된다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  배우들은 관객과 연기할 때 더 긴장하게 된다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  관객이 참여하는 연극은 편안하게 즐기기 힘들다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I heard you watched a play yesterday? The play is said to be interesting, so I'm thinking of going to see it on the weekend.\nWoman : Is that so? I wasn't good There were many times when I asked the audience to come to the stage in the middle of the play. I don't know how nervous I was every time. In addition, when people come forward, the flow of the play is cut off and it takes a long time....... This kind of play doesn't concentrate well and it's just burdensome.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  관객이 참여하는 연극은 편안하게 즐기기 힘들다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "16. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  원하는 일을 하면서 살고 싶다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  공부를 하면서 평생을 보내고 싶다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  한 가지 일보다 다양한 일을 해 보고 싶다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  전공 공부와 관련 있는 현장 경험을 쌓고 싶다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : I heard that you are going to quit the company and prepare for graduate school. But isn't it too late to start studying again now?\nWoman : It was too late. But you can't spend your whole life doing something you don't want to do. Actually, I've always wanted to do construction work since I was young. It's a little later than others, but I'm going to take this opportunity to study.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  원하는 일을 하면서 살고 싶다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [14~17]다음 대화를 듣고 여자가 어떤 생각을 하고 있는지 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "17. (4점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  제품을 체험해 볼 수 있는 기회가 있어야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  제품의 사용 기한을 분명하게 표시해 줘야 한다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  소비자는 여러 종류의 제품을 비교해 보고 사야 한다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  물건을 살 때는 사용하면서 들어갈 비용도 살펴야 한다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Ugh, why is the ink on this printer so expensive?\nWoman : That's right. I also use that product, but I kept thinking about it when I bought ink.\nMan : If you buy a few more times of ink like this, it will cost more than buying a new printer.\nWoman : It really is. I'm using an electric toothbrush at home, but it costs more to change the toothbrush than the electric toothbrush. The belly button is bigger than the belly. Next time, I'll have to consider this part well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  물건을 살 때는 사용하면서 들어갈 비용도 살펴야 한다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 대화가 끝난 후에 남자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "18. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  여자와 테니스를 치러 간다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  운동 계획을 다시 세워 본다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  기숙사 앞에서 여자를 만난다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  기숙사에 운동화를 가지러 간다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Don't you go to exercise these days?\nMan : I worked out hard as I planned until last month, but it's not as good as I thought these days.\nWoman : Is that so? Then why don't we go play tennis while we're talking?\nMan : Now? It's good to go play tennis, but sneakers are in the dormitory.\nWoman : Then let's meet here in 20 minutes.\nMan : Yes. OK .",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  기숙사에 운동화를 가지러 간다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 대화가 끝난 후에 남자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "19. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  수미에게 연락을 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  파티 장소를 찾아본다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  송별 파티를 하러 간다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  여자와 함께 수미를 만난다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : When did Sumi say she was going?\nWoman: 28th. Oh, there's less than a week left.\nMan : Why don't we have a farewell party?\nWoman : good Where is the best place for the party? It's the end of the year, so you have to hurry. I'll look into that now. But shouldn't we ask Sumi if she has time? You must be busy these days....... I'm going to meet Sumi later, so I'll ask her then.\nMan : Yes, please.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  파티 장소를 찾아본다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [18~20] 대화가 끝난 후에 남자가 이어서 할 행동으로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오.",
            "question"      : "20. (3점) ",
            "option_1"      : "①  이전 행사 자료를 찾아본다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  참가자들의 항공료를 알아본다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  항공료 지급에 필요한 서류를 받는다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  행사 참가자들에게 안내 메일을 보낸다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Minsu, how many people from how many countries will participate in this event?\nMen: A total of 12 countries, 35 people will participate.\nWoman : Then, first of all, if they are coming from overseas, please calculate the airfare first. And when I pay the airfare, I also send an email to inform them what documents participants have to pay. It's an important event, so please take care not to make mistakes and take a good look at the previous materials.\nMan : Yes. I will take care of it well.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  참가자들의 항공료를 알아본다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "21. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. ",
            "option_1"      : "①  남자는 작품의 내용을 수십 번씩 고쳤다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  남자는 작품을 위해서 여기저기 돌아다녔다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  남자는 요리사들에게 음식 정보를 알려 주었다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  남자는 생활 속 맛있는 요리들을 많이 발견했다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Recently, I came to Mr. Kim Seong-ho, who is gaining a lot of popularity with his work called 'Food competition'. 'Food competition' is a story about chefs who compete in cooking. Sir, what was difficult about making this work?\nMan : Actually, there's no place I haven't been to all over the country to make this work. Because I had to find out the dishes that I can't taste in my daily life. I visited famous domestic chefs, but I couldn't get the information easily. Also, I had to draw a picture of the cooking process, so I tried to cook it myself and tried it dozens of times. Until the taste is expressed in the picture. Those processes were a little difficult.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  남자는 작품을 위해서 여기저기 돌아다녔다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [21~22] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "22. 남자는 누구인지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  만화가",
            "option_2"      : "②  연극 제작자",
            "option_3"      : "③  책 디자이너",
            "option_4"      : "④  요리 전문가",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Recently, I came to Mr. Kim Seong-ho, who is gaining a lot of popularity with his work called 'Food competition'. 'Food competition' is a story about chefs who compete in cooking. Sir, what was difficult about making this work?\nMan : Actually, there's no place I haven't been to all over the country to make this work. Because I had to find out the dishes that I can't taste in my daily life. I visited famous domestic chefs, but I couldn't get the information easily. Also, I had to draw a picture of the cooking process, so I tried to cook it myself and tried it dozens of times. Until the taste is expressed in the picture. Those processes were a little difficult.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  만화가",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "23. 남자는 무엇을 하고 있는지 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  고속도로 휴게소의 활용 방안을 소개하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  고속도로 휴게소의 이미지 변화를 제안하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  고속도로 휴게소의 개선 방향에 대해 설명하고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  고속도로 휴게소의 발전 가능성에 대해 전망하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Our Korean Expressway Corporation has made great efforts to improve the service of the highway rest area. To date, we have improved the environment of restaurants and toilets and conducted sales of local specialties. I surveyed what customers think about these changes through a survey. Most of the customers were satisfied with the changed rest area. However, there was also a demand to diversify the restaurant menu and increase the space to sit and relax. Therefore, we plan to develop a variety of menus that take into account the taste of each generation, and further expand the rest area in the rest area.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  고속도로 휴게소의 개선 방향에 대해 설명하고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [23~24] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "24. 대한도로공사가 고객들에게 설문 조사를 실시한 이유를 고르십시오",
            "option_1"      : "①  휴게소 이용 고객의 특징을 분석하기 위해",
            "option_2"      : "②  휴게소의 물품 판매 현황을 조사하기 위해",
            "option_3"      : "③  휴게소의 새로운 사업 방향을 살펴보기 위해",
            "option_4"      : "④  휴게소 서비스에 대한 만족도를 평가하기 위해",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : Our Korean Expressway Corporation has made great efforts to improve the service of the highway rest area. To date, we have improved the environment of restaurants and toilets and conducted sales of local specialties. I surveyed what customers think about these changes through a survey. Most of the customers were satisfied with the changed rest area. However, there was also a demand to diversify the restaurant menu and increase the space to sit and relax. Therefore, we plan to develop a variety of menus that take into account the taste of each generation, and further expand the rest area in the rest area.",
            "correctAnswer" : "④  휴게소 서비스에 대한 만족도를 평가하기 위해",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "25. 여자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  사과 방송을 하면 기업의 매출이 늘어나게 된다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  올바른 기업 문화를 위해 소비자의 역할이 중요하다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  진실한 사과는 상대방의 긍정적인 반응을 이끌어 낼 수 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  텔레비전 광고는 기업의 이미지를 변화시키는 데 도움이 된다.",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Did you know that you can earn trust through an apology? One day, a famous department store was reclaiming returned products. A customer who saw this uploaded the video on the Internet. Soon, there was a lot of complaints from consumers. Then the department store sent out an apology broadcast through a television advertisement. The boss came to the broadcast in person and admitted his mistake and apologized. Surprisingly, the sales of the department store rose by 14% after the apology broadcast. Because the honest apology broadcast moved the hearts of customers. Don't try to cover it up or deny it when you make a mistake, but make an honest ag-notation(សំគាល់). you will be able to give the other person a deeper faith.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  진실한 사과는 상대방의 긍정적인 반응을 이끌어 낼 수 있다.",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [25~26] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "26. 여자가 제시한 주장의 근거로 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  구체적 사례",
            "option_2"      : "②  전문가 의견",
            "option_3"      : "③  자신의 경험",
            "option_4"      : "④  설문 조사 결과",
            "detail"        : "\nWoman : Did you know that you can earn trust through an apology? One day, a famous department store was reclaiming returned products. A customer who saw this uploaded the video on the Internet. Soon, there was a lot of complaints from consumers. Then the department store sent out an apology broadcast through a television advertisement. The boss came to the broadcast in person and admitted his mistake and apologized. Surprisingly, the sales of the department store rose by 14% after the apology broadcast. Because the honest apology broadcast moved the hearts of customers. Don't try to cover it up or deny it when you make a mistake, but make an honest ag-notation(សំគាល់). you will be able to give the other person a deeper faith.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  구체적 사례",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "27. 남자의 생각으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  대학에서도 봉사 활동 점수를 인정해 줘야 한다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  봉사 활동은 스스로 원해서 할 때 더 의미가 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  학생들이 봉사 활동을 직접 해 보는 것이 중요하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  배울 것이 많은 봉사 활동을 선택하는 것이 필요하다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : These days, high school students struggle to find a place to do volunteer work during vacation. Because the volunteer activity score is used as a college admission material. As a result, there are many students who do it not because they want to do volunteer work, but to force them to get a score. I don't think this kind of volunteer work means anything.\nWoman : That may be a problem, but I think it's also important to experience volunteering through such an opportunity. I started because of the score, but I'm definitely learning while doing volunteer work. I also needed a score when I was in high school, so I went to a nursing home to volunteer, but I was able to learn to be grateful for small things while doing volunteer work.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  봉사 활동은 스스로 원해서 할 때 더 의미가 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [27~28] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오. (각 3점)",
            "question"      : "28. 여자의 생각이나 태도로 맞는 것을 고르십시오.",
            "option_1"      : "①  자료를 제시하며 상대방을 침착하게 설득하고 있다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  문제점을 제기하며 상대방의 의견을 반박하고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  경험한 것을 이야기하며 자신의 의견을 밝히고 있다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  조사 내용을 보여 주며 자신의 생각을 주장하고 있다.",
            "detail"        : "\nMan : These days, high school students struggle to find a place to do volunteer work during vacation. Because the volunteer activity score is used as a college admission material. As a result, there are many students who do it not because they want to do volunteer work, but to force them to get a score. I don't think this kind of volunteer work means anything.\nWoman : That may be a problem, but I think it's also important to experience volunteering through such an opportunity. I started because of the score, but I'm definitely learning while doing volunteer work. I also needed a score when I was in high school, so I went to a nursing home to volunteer, but I was able to learn to be grateful for small things while doing volunteer work.",
            "correctAnswer" : "③  경험한 것을 이야기하며 자신의 의견을 밝히고 있다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "29. 이 뉴스의 제목으로 가장 알맞은 것을 고르십시오. (4점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  라면시장, 홍보경쟁치열해",
            "option_2"      : "②  라면 업체, 국민 건강 지키기에 나서",
            "option_3"      : "③  라면의 새 바람, 재료 선택부터 달라져",
            "option_4"      : "④  다양해진 라면 맛, 전체 판매량에 영향 끼쳐",
            "detail"        : "\nFemale : Recently, there has been a trend among ramen companies to make less salty ramen. Reporter Lee Jin-soo will give you the detailed news.\nMan : There is a growing perception that excessive sodium intake can cause various diseases. Meanwhile, ramen companies have announced that they will reduce the amount of sodium in ramen by up to 15 percent for public health. He also said that he will gradually reduce the amount of sodium because sudden reductions in the amount could change the taste of ramen. However, this is not the first time ramen companies have campaigned to reduce sodium. It is time for ramen companies to make sincere efforts to prevent such announcements from becoming a means of promoting new products.",
            "correctAnswer" : "②  라면 업체, 국민 건강 지키기에 나서",
            "score"         : "4"
        },
        {
            "sections"      : "※ [29~30] 다음 내용을 듣고 물음에 답하십시오.",
            "question"      : "30. 들은 내용으로 맞는 것을 고르십시오. (3점)",
            "option_1"      : "①  나트륨 양은 라면 맛에 영향을 준다.",
            "option_2"      : "②  덜 짠 라면이 인기를 많이 끌고 있다.",
            "option_3"      : "③  라면 속 나트륨의 양은 최대 15%가 적절하다.",
            "option_4"      : "④  라면의 나트륨 줄이기는 처음으로 시도되었다.",
            "detail"        : "\nFemale : Recently, there has been a trend among ramen companies to make less salty ramen. Reporter Lee Jin-soo will give you the detailed news.\nMan : There is a growing perception that excessive sodium intake can cause various diseases. Meanwhile, ramen companies have announced that they will reduce the amount of sodium in ramen by up to 15 percent for public health. He also said that he will gradually reduce the amount of sodium because sudden reductions in the amount could change the taste of ramen. However, this is not the first time ramen companies have campaigned to reduce sodium. It is time for ramen companies to make sincere efforts to prevent such announcements from becoming a means of promoting new products.",
            "correctAnswer" : "①  나트륨 양은 라면 맛에 영향을 준다.",
            "score"         : "3"
        }
    ]
}
